<?xml version="1.0"?>
<KnowledgeBaseConfiguration xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:space="preserve">
  <Id>8261bcf9-c40a-4591-bbea-9c069bb4ff62</Id>
  <DisplayName>Orchestrator Metrics over Threshold</DisplayName>
  <CreatedTime>2020-12-18T23:41:27.6641155Z</CreatedTime>
  <ModifiedTime>2020-12-18T23:41:27.6641155Z</ModifiedTime>
  <RelatedInformation />
  <PossibleResolution>
    <string>Use reports that come with Cisco Process Orchestrator to examine the historical values for the metrics. </string>
    <string />
    <string>If memory utilization metric is consistently higher than the threshold, examine configuration of the Orchestrator and consider the number of targets, target properties, global variables, process definitions and other configuration objects defined in the environment.  If the number of configuration objects is large, a high memory utilization is probably normal for your environment. Increase the thresholds by modifying relevant rows in the 'Orchestrator Self Monitoring Thresholds' global variable, to avoid getting "false" alerts.</string>
    <string />
    <string>If the number of running processes is consistently higher than the threshold, examine your process and target configurations. If the server is responsive to Console, Web Console and/or Northbound Web Service requests, the higher load might be normal for your environment. To eliminate "false" alerts increase the thresholds by modifying relevant rows in the 'Orchestrator Self Monitoring Thresholds' global variable.</string>
    <string />
    <string>If the alert was generated by a "spike" in the metric, then the condition was temporary and alert could be safely resolved.</string>
    <string />
    <string>If the memory utilization and number of running processes were high for extended period of time and then dropped back to normal, this might indicate that the server was backlogged. Examine the processes that ran at that time and consider reworking them to reduce the impact on the environment (for example, consider eliminating loops over tables, turn off archival and resume options for processes, use asynchronous process execution for chid processes).</string>
    <string />
    <string>If the memory or number of processes metrics are consistently growing, contact Technical Support. This might be an indicate of a memory leak and further diagnosis would be required.</string>
  </PossibleResolution>
  <PossibleCause>
    <string>This condition could be caused by a number of reasons (some of them are benign):</string>
    <string>- Memory utilization is directly proportional to the number of targets, properties, global variables, process definitions within the environment. Higher memory utilization would be normal for an environment with large number of such configuration objects.</string>
    <string>- Memory and number of running and in-memory processes is directly proportional to the amount of work (number of process instances) being executed by the Orchestrator. Higher values for these metrics might be normal for a system execution a large process load.</string>
    <string>- Consistently growing number of running or in-memory processes might indicate that the Orchestrator is backlogged and cannot keep up with the process load</string>
    <string>- Consistently increasing memory utilization (without corresponding increase in the number of running and in-memory processes) might indicate a memory leak</string>
  </PossibleCause>
  <Summary>
    <string>One of several important self-monitoring metrics for Cisco Process Orchestrator exceeded a pre-defined threshold.</string>
  </Summary>
</KnowledgeBaseConfiguration>